<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>On the death of Sir Tho. Armstrong in ansvver to a late treasonable libel dispers'd by the factions.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A53351</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99834511</idno>
  <idno type="VID">39012</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240945576</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing O306</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224205</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99834511</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99834511e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A53351)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 39012)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1817:26)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>On the death of Sir Tho. Armstrong in ansvver to a late treasonable libel dispers'd by the factions.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed and sold by Nath. Thompson at the entrance into the Old-Spring-Garden near Charing-Cross,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1684.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Armstrong was executed for his part in the Rye House Plot.</note>
                  <note>Verse - "Thou monster Armstrong, cou'd thy soul return".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Armstrong, Thomas, --  Sir, 1624?-1684 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Rye House Plot, 1683 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:39012:1"/>
            <head>On the DEATH of Sir Tho. Armstrong; IN ANSWER TO A LATE Treasonous LIBEL Dispers'd by the Factious.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>THou Monster <hi>Armstrong,</hi> cou'd thy Soul return</l>
               <l>But a few Minutes from her <hi>Sulph'rous Urn,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To see the Joys that Loyal men imploy,</l>
               <l>At thy deserv'd, tho' Fatal Destiny:</l>
               <l>It wou'd (if possible) thy Pain increase,</l>
               <l>And add new Tortures to <hi>Hell</hi>'s Miseries:</l>
               <l>Hadst thou still Safe been in thy <hi>Trayt'rous</hi> Flight,</l>
               <l>Thou hadst not come up to this wicked height;</l>
               <l>For th' <hi>Treasons</hi> that Thou Living did'st intend,</l>
               <l>Thou ne'r repent'st of at thy Fatal End:</l>
               <l>Just thus dy'd <hi>Peters, Harrison</hi> and <hi>Pride,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Much better <hi>Catiline</hi> and <hi>Cethegus</hi> dy'd.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>If we shou'd tell how much he is too blame,</l>
               <l>'Twould for a Volumn, be a Copious Theme:</l>
               <l>If once (if true) he Loyal were, 'tis all</l>
               <l>In his whole Life, that we can Virtuous call:</l>
               <l>But we have too much reason to believe,</l>
               <l>That even Then he did his King deceive;</l>
               <l>And so did never Change, was still a Rogue,</l>
               <l>Still Courting whatsoever Power in Vogue:</l>
               <l>And now his <hi>Quarters,</hi> most deserv'dly stand</l>
               <l>As <hi>Scare-Crows</hi> to the rest o'th' <hi>Factious Band;</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:39012:2"/>
               <l>The Peaceful <hi>Grave</hi> to this day ne'r contain'd,</l>
               <l>A <hi>Carcas</hi> like to His with <hi>Treason</hi> stain'd.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>But sure his Monstrous Spirit 'gain is risen</l>
               <l>Out of the dismal hole of <hi>Hells</hi> dark <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>son,</l>
               <l>Has got a short Reprieve, and now Indicts</l>
               <l>All that this Horrid Impious Villain Writes:</l>
               <l>Nothing but <hi>Hells</hi> Dear Imp cou'd e'er devise,</l>
               <l>Such Horrid <hi>Treasons,</hi> Monstrous <hi>Blasphemies,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Cou'd e'er rake up that <hi>Holy Marlyrs,</hi> Dust,</l>
               <l>Of our First Sacred <hi>Charles,</hi> the Good, the Just:</l>
               <l>Be Judge just Heaven, judge all on Earth below,</l>
               <l>Judge, and then tell me, if you er're cou'd shew</l>
               <l>One Vicious Act in the whole Blessed Reign</l>
               <l>Of that most Sacred Prince, by <hi>Traytors</hi> slain:</l>
               <l>And if into your Memory you call</l>
               <l>The true <hi>Idaea</hi> of the Original,</l>
               <l>You'll find in's <hi>Sons,</hi> he Copy'd is as True,</l>
               <l>As e'er in Imitation <hi>Titian</hi> drew:</l>
               <l>Our Sacred <hi>Charles</hi> is so averse to Blood,</l>
               <l>That (if he any Fault have) he's too Good,</l>
               <l>Shews too much Mercy to his <hi>Harden'd Foes,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That wou'd Himself and Progeny Depose:</l>
               <l>Can the most Brazen'd Face o'th <hi>Factious Crew</hi>
               </l>
               <l>In Royal JAMES the least Injustice shew?</l>
               <l>No, tis their Grievance that the World Proclaims,</l>
               <l>No Truer Friend, no Juster man than JAMES:</l>
               <l>What Subjects then can e'r refuse t'obey,</l>
               <l>The Just and equal Poise of <hi>Charles</hi>'s Sway?</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>We need not (<hi>Rebels</hi>) on you Vengeance call,</l>
               <l>God lets the Rod of Justice on You fall;</l>
               <l>The Heavenly Wisdom all your Actions saw</l>
               <l>Your Preach of Faith, o'th Kings, and of his Law</l>
               <l>Since each of you is become Heavens Foe,</l>
               <l>Heaven▪s Justice does the Punishment bestow.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Prin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed and Sold by <hi>Nath. Thompson</hi> at the Entrance into the <hi>Old-Spring-Garden</hi> near <hi>Charing-Cross,</hi> 1684.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>